Joshua Logan Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Writings File, 1925-1988 (Box 129-179)
  - Logan, Joshua (Box 139)
    - Scripts
      - Mulligan Guards
        - Other titles
          - Sing Us a Song, Ned, 1970, (3 folders)
      - On Borrowed Time, miscellaneous pages, 1978, undated
      - Picnic
        - Miscellaneous pages, 1980-1981, undated, (2 folders)
        - Lyrics, 1980-1981
      - Rip Van Winkle (Box 167)
        - Drafts, 1975-1976, (2 folders)
        - Lyrics and music, undated
      - South Pacific, miscellaneous pages, undated
      - Weddin' Day
        - Correspondence, 1986
        - Drafts, 1986-1988, (5 folders); (3 folders) (Box 168)
        - Revisions by Hugh Martin, 1986, (2 folders)
        - Miscellaneous pages, 1986-1988, (2 folders)
        - Lyrics, 1986-1987
        - Notes, 1986, undated (Box 169)
        - Other title, The Member of the Wedding, draft by Hugh Martin, 1986
      - Wish You Were Here
        - Final version, 1952, 1973, undated, (2 folders)
        - Miscellaneous pages, [1952]
      - The Wisteria Trees
        - Preface, undated
        - Original version, 1949, 1955, (2 folders)
        - Revised version, 1982, (2 folders)
        - Miscellaneous pages, 1955-1982, undated
    - Short stories, 1944, undated
    - Song lyrics, 1973-1987, undated (Box 170)
    - Speeches and tributes, 1962-1982, undated
  - Logan, Nedda Harrigan See Containers 132-133, Dalrymple, Jean
  - MacArthur, Charles See Container 136, Hecht, Ben
  - Mackilroy, Arnald See Container 175, Pittman, Bruce
  - Macomber, Doris, A Web of Light, 1969, (2 folders)
  - Manber, David
    - The Bait, 1971
    - The Party Crasher, 1971
  - Mandel, Loring, Project Immortality, 1966
  - Mann, Edward Andrew, and Maurice Scofield, The Maltese Cross, undated See also Container 177, Scofield, Maurice, (1 folder) (Box 171)
  - Marchant, William See Container 137, Inge, William
  - Martin, Hugh See Containers 167-169, Logan, Joshua, Scripts, Weddin' Day
  - Martin, Norman See Container 171, Mister Roberts
  - McAndrews, Suzanne Simon See Container 138, Leontovich, Eugenie
  - McClain, John, No Visible Means, 1953, undated
  - McClain, John, and Thomas W. Phipps, Extra Man, undated
  - McDonald, John L., Vitamin K and Iron, 1981
  - McEvoy, J. P., Shanghai Diary, undated
  - Meranze, David S., and Marc Allen Zagoren, Dutch Treat, 1970
  - Meyerson, Ed, On With the Dance! 1972
  - Millholland, Charles Bruce, Faun, undated See also Container 136, Hecht, Ben
  - Mister Roberts
    - Music and lyrics, Norman Martin and Stanley Ralph Ross, 1984, undated
    - Screenplays (Box 172)
      - Nugent, Frank S., 1954
      - Patrick, John, 1954 See also Container 174, Patrick, John
    - Shooting script, 1955
  - Morgan, Al, To Sit on a Horse, 1970
  - Morris, Edmund, The Careful Man, 1962, (2 folders)
  - Nelson, Wallace W., poems, 1982, undated
  - The New Year, undated, (2 folders)
  - Noble, William See Container 136, Herlihy, James Leo
  - Norton, Mary, The Magic Bed-Knob, undated, (2 folders) (Box 173)
  - Nugent, Frank S. See Container 172, Mister Roberts
  - O'Flainn, Seamus, Siege, Being the Dramatic Effect of Histrionic Gammy Rays upon the Average Sean Brendan Shaw, 1976
  - Olgga, Branka See Container 174, Pacific, Al
  - Osborn, Paul
    - A Musical Play, undated
    - Sayonara, 1956, undated, (2 folders)
    - Tomorrow's Monday, undated
    - The World of Suzie Wong, 1959
    - Unidentified play, undated (Box 174)
  - Pacific, Al, and Branka Olgga, Earthshake, undated
  - Pagnol, Marcel
    - The Baker's Wife, undated
    - Judas, undated
  - Patrick, John See also Container 172, Mister Roberts
    - Confession, undated
    - The Doctor Will See You, Now, undated
    - The Indictment, undated
    - Isn't Everybody? undated
    - It's a Dog's Life, undated
    - People! undated
    - Progression, undated
    - Satan's Sister, undated (Box 175)
    - Strategy, undated
    - Tenacity, undated
    - That's Not My Mother, 1976
  - Phillips, Cassandra, The Phoebe Sparks Show, undated
  - Phillips, K. Hart, untitled play synopsis, 1947
  - Phipps, Thomas W. See Container 171, McClain, John
  - Pittman, Bruce, and Arnald Mackilroy, Hearts & Flowers, 1981
  - Porter, Charné, Hole in the Wall, 1979
  - Pressburger, Emeric See Container 153, Logan, Joshua, Scripts, Careful! (He Might Hear You)
  - Quantrill, Jay Alan, The Jeremiad, undated
  - Reel, Arthur
    - Dead Souls, 1974
    - The Nose, 1974, undated
  - Rifkin, Shepard
    - George Said No, undated
    - The Glacier Watchers, undated
    - To Sleep with Tigers, undated (Box 176)
  - Rodewald, Elizabeth, Sixty-Seventh Street, undated, (2 folders)
  - Rodgers, Richard, and Lorenz Hart, I Married an Angel, [1938]
  - Ross, Stanley Ralph See Container 171, Mister Roberts
  - Roussin, Andre, Island Fling, 1949
  - Ruffini, Gene, Bon Voyage, undated
  - Russell, Robert
    - Bang the Drum Slowly, undated
    - That River of Gold, undated, (2 folders)
  - Sabath, Bernard, The End of the Conversation, 1974 (Box 177)
  - Sahloff, Ivan, Zero to Hero, undated
  - Scofield, Maurice, Savonarola, undated See also Containers 170-171, Mann, Edward Andrew, and Maurice Scofield
  - Seldin-Schwartz, Ethel See Container 137, Horvath, Joan
  - Seven Hills of Worcester, 1960, undated, (2 folders)
  - Slade, Susan, Ready When You Are, C.B., 1964
  - Smith, Leonard Stewart, Jr., Prelude to a Tea Party, undated
  - South Pacific, revised temporary script, 1957
  - Steele, William J., To Have and to Hold, 1941-1976, undated
  - Stewart, Michael, Harrigan and Hart, 1985 (Box 178)
  - Stricklyn, Ray, and Charlotte Chandler, Tennessee Williams: Confessions of a Nightingale, undated
  - Szold, Bernard, Moonstone, 1946
  - Taylor, Richard D., The Death of Reverend J. Lane Borden, undated
  - Thompson, G. Clare, Decadent Angel, undated
  - Turgenev, Ivan, A Month in the Country, undated
  - Vane, Norman Thaddeus, Written in an Indian's Blood, 1971
  - Wersba, Barbara, The Dream Watcher, undated
  - Wilcox, Henry B., Tent Show, 1976, undated
  - Williams, Emlyn, The Saga of a Slave, and a Slave Driver, 1985
  - Williams, Herschel V., An Indecent Obsession, undated
  - Wolas, Eva See Container 138, Lamkin, Speed
  - Young, Burt, Apple II or III, 1982, undated (Box 179)
  - Zagoren, Marc Allen See Container 171, Meranze, David S.
  - Zindel, Paul, Dorothy, undated
  - Unidentified, undated, (5 folders)
- Miscellany, 1920-1992 (Box 179-184)
  Autographs, awards, certificates, newspaper clippings, notes, and printed material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Addresses, 1953-1955, undated (Box 179)
  - Art work, undated See also Oversize
  - Autographs, 1954-1986, undated
  - Awards, certificates, and diplomas, 1949-1989, n.d See also Oversize
  - Newspaper clippings
    - Heggen, Thomas, 1949
    - Leatherbee, Mary Lee Logan, 1930-1972
    - Logan, Joshua, 1920-1989, undated, (8 folders); (5 folders) (Box 180, Box 181, Box 182)
    - Logan, Nedda Harrigan (Box 183)
      - Actors' Fund of America, 1962-1987, (2 folders)
      - General, 1940-1992, undated
    - Logan, Susan Harrigan, 1977-1982
    - Logan, Thomas Heggen, 1967, undated
    - O'Neil, Barbara, 1932-1940
  - Notes, 1985-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - Party memoranda, 1959-1982, undated
  - Printed material, 1927-1987, undated, (3 folders) (Box 184)
  - Scrapbooks, 1931-1976 See Oversize
- Oversize, 1923-1986 (Box OV 1-37)
  Oversize items consisting mostly of awards, certificates, blueprints, scrapbooks, production budget sheets, and printed material.
  Organized and described according to the series, folders, and boxes from which the items were removed.
  - Production File (Box OV 1)
    - Bus Stop
      - Publicity, circa 1956 (Container 99)
    - Careful! (He Might Hear You)
      - Financial papers, 1971 (Container 100)
    - Kind Sir (Box OV 2)
      - Working papers, technical, 1953 (Container 112)
    - Middle of the Night
      - Working papers, seating chart, 1955-1956 (Container 114) Core Collection Item No. 92
    - Picnic (play)
      - Working papers, technical, 1952 (Container 120)
    - Mister Roberts (play) (Box OV 3)
      - Publicity, 1947-1948 (Container 116)
    - Mr. President
      - Publicity, 1962 (Container 117)
    - Nightclub act
      - Working papers, technical, 1985, undated (Container 118)
    - Picnic (play)
      - Publicity, 1952-1953 (Container 120)
    - South Pacific (play) (Box OV 4)
      - Publicity, general, 1948-1949 (Container 124)
    - Tall Story
      - Financial papers, 1959 (Container 125)
    - Why I Went Crazy
      - Working papers, 1969 (Container 126)
    - Wish You Were Here
      - Working papers, technical, 1952 (Container 128)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 5)
    - Awards, certificates, and diplomas, 1950, 1986 (Container 179)
    - Scrapbooks (Box OV 6)
      - Blue Denim, 1958
      - Bus Stop (Box OV 7)
        - 1956
        - 1956-1957 (Box OV 8)
      - Culver Military Academy, Culver, Ind., 1923 (Box OV 9)
      - Fanny (Box OV 10)
        - 1954-1956
        - 1960 (Box OV 11)
        - 1960-1961 (Box OV 12)
        - 1961 (Box OV 13)
      - Happy Birthday, 1946-1947 (Box OV 14)
      - Kind Sir, 1953-1954 (Box OV 15)
      - Middle of the Night (Box OV 16)
        - 1955-1958
        - 1956-1957 (Box OV 17)
      - Miscellaneous (Box OV 18)
        - 1948-1956
        - 1948-1956 (Box OV 19)
        - 1950-1954 (Box OV 20)
        - 1975 (Box OV 21)
        - 1976 (Box OV 22)
        - 1976 (Box OV 23)
      - Mister Roberts (Box OV 24)
        - 1948
        - 1954-1955 (Box OV 25)
      - Paint Your Wagon, 1969 (Box OV 26)
      - Picnic (Box OV 27)
        - 1952-1954
        - 1955-1957 (Box OV 28)
      - Sayonara (Box OV 29)
        - 1953-1958
        - 1956 (Box OV 30)
      - South Pacific (Box OV 31)
        - 1949
        - 1949-1955 (Box OV 32)
        - 1957-1959 (Box OV 33)
      - Tall Story, 1959-1960 (Box OV 34)
      - University Players, 1931-1932 (Box OV 35)
      - Wish You Were Here, 1952-1954 (Box OV 36)
      - The Wisteria Trees, 1950-1955 (Box OV 37)